Guide to the Laboratory for Elementary Particle Physics photographs, 1950-2005.
Laboratory for Elementary Particle Physics photographs
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Laboratory for Elementary Particle Physics photographs, 1950-2005.
14-22-3483
Cornell University.Laboratory for Elementary Particle Physics (LEPP).
7.6 cubic ft; 12 drawers of negatives;125 volumes of photographs with index.
Photographs, Scrapbooks
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes material documenting events, the Wilson Synchrotron Laboratory and work done at the lab.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes photographs, slides, negatives and scrapbooks taken/collected by Donald Miller, a graphics designer, documenting events, the Wilson Synchrotron Laboratory and work done at the lab.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Miller, Donald W.; Cornell University.Dept. of Physics.; Wilson Synchrotron Laboratory (Cornell University)
Subjects:
Nuclear physics--Research.; Particle accelerators--Construction.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Color slides.; Negatives.; Scrapbooks.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Negatives (Box 1-5)
- Synchrotron scrapbook, ca. 1964 (Box 6)
- Photographs (Box 7-10)
  A list of these photos with their media type and size is available upon request.
  - CLEO II Drift Chamber (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 2 GeV (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 2 GeV Choke Sol. Goldberg 3987-0, 1950-09-14 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 10 GeV Magnet End (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 10 GeV High Bend Magnet (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 10 GeV Magnet with R. R. Wilson and R. Litauer (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 10 GeV Tunnel with R. R. Wilson, R. Litauer, R. Mateas and ? (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 10 GeV Steering Coil with R. Litauer Ref. on back: Neg File 6711, Roll 3, Frame 12 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - M. Tigner, R. R. Wilson, B. McDaniel (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - M. Tigner, R. R. Wilson, B. McDaniel, K. Berkelman (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 10 Gev Steering Coil with R. Litauer Ref. on back: Neg File 6711, Roll 3, Frame 10 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 10 Gev Electronics with R. Litauer File 6711 Roll 3 Frame 6 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Table Top Apparatus (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 10 Gev Electronics with R. Litauer and RR Wilson File 6711 Roll 3 Frame 3 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 10 Gev Electronics with R. Litauer File 6711 Roll 3 Frame 2 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 10 Gev Electronics with R. Litauer File 6711 Roll 3 Frame 7 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Table Top Apparatus (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Table Top Apparatus (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Table Top Apparatus, with ? person Sol Goldberg photo (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Physics Today July 2005 p 75 Robert Bacher Obituary (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Control Room with typed description of control desk Sol Goldberg Photo 4713-E, 1949-07-18 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - RF Structure, Label 227 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Clock Tower and Cayuga Lake, Label 226 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Vacuum Chamber, Sol Goldberg 5023-0, 1949-10-22 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 2 Gev Magnets and Beam Line, Photo Science Studies 10399-6 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 2 Gev Magnets PS10399-13 and 10 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Linac Stack, Beam Lines (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - “First Two 9-cell prototype cavities for TESLA” (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Drift Chamber Wires and female stringer (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Drift Caamber and two stringers (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Drift Chamber, Office of Univ. Relations, 78119 Roll 3 Frame 3 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Cleo I (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Drift Chamber (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - RF Cryostat 1 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - RF Cryostat 2 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - RF Cryostat 3 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - RF Cryostat 4 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - RF Electronics Rack (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - RF Cryostat 5 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - CERN, Stanford, Fermilab (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Drawing of 10 Gev Magnet End-“Cerenkov Effect” (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - End View of CLEO I (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Cryogenic Piping (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - CESR Superconducting Cavity (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - R F Waveguide (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - 10 Gev Tunnel with CESR labeled “0620079-001” (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - CLEO I and visitors on walkway, Sol Goldberg 6871-25-6 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Helen Edwards at Control Desk, Sol Goldberg 6871-29-18 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - People at Meeting, Ken Lovelace, John Dewire ..., Sol Goldberg 6711-9-20 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - People at Meeting, Sol Goldberg 6711-9-22 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Two men stacking magnet laminations, Sol Goldberg 6871-21-9 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Stacking Magnets, Sol Goldberg 6871-21-16 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Stacking Magnets, Sol Goldberg 6871-21-13 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Helen Edwards, Sol Goldberg 6871-1-9 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - CLEO II outline (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Superconducting RF (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - CLEO I dE/dx Chamber (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Separators (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Cryostats (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - RF Structures (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - 2 GeV Background, RR Wilson, B. McDaniel, 12 others, Photo Sciences Studios 10399-5 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - K. Berkelman, S Gray, D. Widger with Plaque (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - CESR Plan (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - B. McDaniel at control desk, Sol Goldberg 6871-4-16A (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - B. McDaniel reflected in spark chamber, Sol Goldberg 6871-20-21 6871-20-17 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - B. McDaniel (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Poster Display titled “Cornell University High Energy Physics” (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - B. McDaniel, R. Mateas and visitors in tunnel Sol Goldberg 6871-25-23 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Cryostat (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Cryostat (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Colored Superconducting RF Cutaway drawing, greeting cards (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - “Greeting from CESR” 11 December 1979 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - CLEO II White on Black (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Drift Chamber End Plate (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Artist drawing, single ring, 300 MeV synchrotron (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Artist cutaway drawing, with and without LOE building, File No. 0500475 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Four magnets and vacuum chambers labeled “1.5 GeV ELECTRON SYNCHROTRON IN TEMPORARY STAGING AREA” (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - H. Padamsee “RF Superconductivity 2004” (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Cornell Physics Department 3/2003 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Conference/Celebration participants, Cornell Univ Photography, C. Harrington, File 37/01, 36/01 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - “Tuning the Beam” by Bridget Meeds, Synchrotron Haiku (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - A 10 GeV beam insertion device, File No. 0661192 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - CLEO II End view, File No. 0800 495 098 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - 10 GeV Tunnel with CESR (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - “300 MeV Synchrotron Electron Pair Spectrometer 1949” Photo Sci. Services 5461, 1950-03-24 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - CLEO II, File No. 1610089-001 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - File No. 0800 388-075 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - File No. 0800 385-005 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - E. Von Borstal in early 10 Gev tunnel with unidentified person, Sol Goldberg 6871-7-32 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - E. Von Borstal and unidentified person in Linac stack, Sol Goldberg 6871-14-17 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Very early apparatus- on back marked Lawrence Radiation Lab- University of CA. – Morgue, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Muffin pan SRF (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Cylindrical SRF (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Inner Detector, File No. 0821094-003 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - E. Von Borstal and unidentified person in Linac stack, Sol Goldberg 6871-15-11 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Goldberg 6871-7-33 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Goldberg 6871-7-27 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Goldberg 6871-15-21 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Goldberg 6871-15-13 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Goldberg 6871-28-14 – Helen Edwards (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Goldberg 6871-25-3 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Goldberg 6871-1-10-Helen Edwards (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Goldberg 6871-1-14-Helen Edwards (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Unknown subject (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Drawing of 1.5 GeV Synchrotron (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - 10 GeV Tunnel 053 tag (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Don Edwards, Sol Goldberg 6871-26-20 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Dan Peterson and Drift Chamber (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - SRF (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Cryogenic Equipment (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Joe Kirchgessner and SRF (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - B. McDaniel 10 GeV Control Desk (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - SSC layout, SSC excavation (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Electronics Rack (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Electronics Board 1 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Electronics Board 2 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - 1.5 GeV Synchrotron-mid 1950s (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Early Hans Bethe, also William Fowler and others (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - B. McDaniel on bicycle, Sol Goldberg 6871-22-21 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - B. McDaniel in 10 Gev Control Room, Sol Goldberg 6832-2-1 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - B. McDaniel, M. Tigner in 10 Gev Control Room, Sol Goldberg 6832-1-12 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - B. McDaniel, RR Wilson at 10 Gev Mock-up (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - B. McDaniel 10 Gev Synchrotron (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - McDaniel and others, Sol Goldberg 6871-22-5 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - McDaniel and unidentified person Sol Goldberg 6871-3-22A (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - McDaniel and Mirrors, Sol Goldberg 6871-20-20 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - McDaniel (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - McDaniel and Mirrors Sol Goldberg 6871-20-21 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - McDaniel and Mirrors Sol Goldberg 6871-21-21 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - McDaniel and Mirrors, Sol Goldberg 6871-21-37 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - McDaniel and 11 others (technicians?) Sol Goldberg 3608 March 18, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - McDaniel with an unidentified woman - Sol Goldberg 6871-21-26 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - McDaniel with about 25 others at 2 Gev Synchrotron, Photo Sci Studio 10299-12 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Observers at 10 Gev tunnel boring machine, Polo barn background Sol Goldberg 667-1-35 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - “300 MeV Synchrotron...Electron Pair Spectrometer...”, Arthur Askin, Mary Beth Sterns, John DeWire (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - 2 Gev Synchrotron, Photo Sci Studio 10399-7 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - 10 GeV Lab Mock-up RR Wilson, R. Mateas, -Sol Goldberg 6871-13-10 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Pair Spectrometer, Sol Goldberg (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - 6871-13-10 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - 10 Gev Pair Spectrometer (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - 10 Gev Beam Hall Sol Goldberg 6832-3-6A (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Pasted together copy of CESR booklet (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - B & W of SRF cavities (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Color print and names of CLEO/LNS/WSU Summer Students, Cornell Univ Photo 878/98-A-4 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - SRF Apparatus (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - 2 Gev Magnet (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - M. Tigner and 10 Gev RF, 3 views (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - 10 GeV Inter magnet view (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - RR Wilson (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - 10 Gev Exp. Beam Lines with labels Sol Goldberg 6871-10-2, 6871-17-19 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Bacher, Wilson, McDaniel, Berkelman, Tigner and unidentified person, Conference 6871-32-29; Wilson and McDaniel 6857-1-23A; Wilson 664-R1-25; Wilson, McDaniel 6871-32-17, 6832-1-9 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Early CESR, mostly apparatus photographed by Goldberg (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Photos labeled LNS 01-14-03 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - “Chess G-Line Const. Pics” (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - “1320800 REV 2000” (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - “Disc burned on Jan 13th” (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Originals of maps, instructions, drawings (N. Mistry ?) for “1988 US Particle Accelerator School” (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Notes, transparencies on “CESR, CESR holiday card, CLEO, CHESS at the Millenium”, 1999-12-10 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Early pictures of Dale Corson (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - D. Corson, B. McDaniel, RR Wilson, Sol Goldberg 2650-C, 1947-03-14 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Interesting prints of people including: Wilson, Bethe, McDaniel, Lederman, Feynman, Yang and a copy of photo from Los Alamos Ranch, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - CLEO II, C. Ball, B. and S. Gittleman, D. Peterson, Grad student twins (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - 2 Gev Artist Drawing (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - CESR Quad end view (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Spool (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Tigner, Berkelman, McDaniel (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - McDaniel (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Award picture with S. Gray, D. Widger, K. Berkelman (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Publicity Poster Material (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - SRF (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - CLEO event display, CLEO II Drift Chamber, Campus View (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Celebrations, CESR Control Room, CHESS (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - People, F. Long, McDaniel, Matyas, Purcell?, Sol Goldberg 6871-25-26 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - CLEO Drift Chamber (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - CLEO Group picture near CLEO detector, Cornell Univ Photo (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Campus View with CESR Ring (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - CLEO I dE/dx chamber (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - CLEO I overall view (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - CLEO I inside view, Inner detector (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - B &W CLEO I overall view (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Drift Chamber and female stringers (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - CLEO I being assembled (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - CLEO I overall view (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Lecture material “Virus to Quark” (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - 2 Gev Assembly of Magnet Photo Sci Service, 1953-04-09 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Campus Views with and without CESR Ring, Cornell Univ Potography 1343/99A (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - “The Science at Wilson Laboratory” (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - SRF Apparatus and Cavities (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Summer student workers, Cornell Univ Photo 878/98A-11 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - McDaniel and Bethe on bicycles in synchrotron tunnel (pre CESR) (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Conference crowds, people, speakers; Cornell Univ Photo 1670-99A,B (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - CESR Vacuum Chamber Elements (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - RR Wilson, others, 10 GeV Mock-up, Early construction; Cornell Univ Photo 6871-21,22 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - K. Berkelman (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - B. McDaniel (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - McDaniel, Wilson, other 2 GeV era (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Photo Sci Studios 8016 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Early group picture of staff with labeled names (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - 2 GeV Talk at 40th Ave, J. DeWire (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - McDaniel in CESR Tunnel (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Fermilab Main Laboratory (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - CESR Tunnel (no People) (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - “New 1.5 BeV Electron Synchrotron”, Cutaway drawings, components, control room (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - CLEO II Early assembly, CsI crystals, components (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - RR Wilson, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Bowling Men’s League, Don Crevelling, John Stiles, Walter Nelson, Harold Utter, 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - “CESR Positrons” Group posed near CLEO I; Control Room “Hail CESR” gathering, G. Brown, D. Rice, M. Billing and others, apparatus, 1979-05-28 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - “Nuclear Studies” -CUSB Printed circuit electronics boards (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - CUSB (Version I) (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Details of CUSB II during construction (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - SRF apparatus with a few people (Box 8, Folder 6-8)
  - “SRF” apparatus, few people, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 9-11)
  - Cornell Univ Photo 337/93-A-15 CLEO II personnel, xerox of article about penguin decay process, 1993-04-15 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Synchrotron Tune Correction Amplifier (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - “Personnel” mostly individuals, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 13-14)
  - Cornell Univ Photo 6871-21-32A, 6711-10-7, 6711-6-6,6857-1-17A Six people in tunnel including R. Talman; 6711-9-15, 6871-19-9, K. Loveless (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Celebration in Control Room, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - SRF apparatus, some labeled (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - SRF Microscope enlargements of defects (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - “Graduate Conference” SRF Microscope enlargements, oscilloscope tracings, KEK installation of SRF (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - same as above (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Microscope enlargements of SRF surface defects (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - SRF microscope enlargements of surface defects (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - SRF microscope enlargements of surface defects (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - SRF microscope enlargements of surface defects (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - SRF microscope enlargements of surface defects (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - SRF microscope enlargements of surface defects (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - SRF microscope enlargements of surface defects (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - SRF microscope enlargements of surface defects (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Example of “starburst” surface defect (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - SRF microscope enlargements of surface defects (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - SRF microscope enlargements of surface defects (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - SRF microscope enlargements of surface defects (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - SRF microscope enlargements of surface defects (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - SRF microscope enlargements of surface defects (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Cornell Univ. B Factory (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Beam Line Drawings, 1990-01-31 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - N. Mistry Drawing “BEE Factory” (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Personnel pictures and recent technicians. Many by Sol Goldberg Cornell Univ Photo, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 28-29)
  - Posed Personnel Y. Orlov, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Various pictures of Y. Orlov (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Personnel, Cornell Univ Photo, some copies of folder 140 above, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - K. Berkelman Cornell univ Photo A50403-2-5A, Y. Orlov, 1986-12 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Bethe, McDaniel, Wilson in pre CESR tunnel, Sol Goldberg Cornell Univ photos, Early 10 GeV personnel (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Sol Goldberg Cornell Univ. Photo, Early 10 GeV personnel photos, most on poster board; R. Bower, A. Broman, N. Mistry, A. Silverman, Film Scanners, C. Chafee, B. McDaniel, P. Stein (Box 8, Folder 34-36)
  - SRF Microscope enlargements of defects (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Worlds Colliding Beam Facilities (Box 8, Folder 37-38)
  - Vacuum Chambers (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - L Nitrogen installation at Wilson Lab (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Newman Lab, September 1948 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Electron Beam Welding (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Laboratory Trucks (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Fermilab apparatus and event display (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Foam Fire Extinguisher test, 2007-04-20 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - CLEO II (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Party setup Wilson,G.Trutt, A.Vanocher (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Parade on State St. “Sam McDermott”, 1950-1959 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - “Misc 08 92” Box in woods (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - LOE Wilson Lab construction (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Photo Science Studios, Newman Lab construction photos and drawings, H. Bethe and others in Ground Breaking ceremony, 1948-09 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Photo Science Studios, #7310-1,2, 1955-02-09 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - B. McDaniel with early cyclotron in Rockefeller, Typed description, Other pictures with RR Wilson, K. Lovelace, others (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - 300 MeV Synchrotron, Newman Lab, drawings, apparatus, shop facilities, personnel, descriptions, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Photo Science - #3633-A – 300 MeV Synchrotron, 1948-04 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - All Photo Science Studios, Cornell 1 BeV synchrotron, personnel, apparatus, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Other drawings, and photos of the Cornell 1 BeV Synchrotron (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - #7722, 1956-01 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Photo Science Studios #7138-A, D, M. Dameron, 1954-08-25 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - #6752-A, D, E, Set of four magnets for early synchrotron, 1953-10-07 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Photo Science Studios, 2 GeV Synchrotron Newman Lab, mostly apparatus, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Apparatus Mostly Vacuum Chambers, 1985-1987 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Mt. Pleasant Cosmic Ray setup, 1964-08 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Photo Science Studios #10458-1,2 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - November 1979 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - “Cosmic Gamma Ray Project”, 1966-10-25 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Balloon Flt. H66-85 Land-Air (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Cosmic Ray Apparatus and person (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Photo Science Studios #8201-3 Cosmic Ray Apparatus and two people (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Photo Science Studio #7722-2A Cosmic Ray Trailer outside Newman Lab. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Photo Science Studio #8201-2 Roof Top Apparatus (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Photo Science Studio #5648-E Cosmic Ray Apparatus, 1950-10-09 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - #5648-A Apparatus on Float in Cayuga Lake, 1950-10-24 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - #5648-D same with description, 1950-10-09 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - #5648-G Dr Vanna T. Cocconi with cosmic recording apparatus, 1950-10-09 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - #5648-F Dr V Cocconi and apparatus in tent, 1950-10-09 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Photo Science Service #4808-A,B,unlabeled Underground Cavern (Salt Mine?) site, apparatus and people, 1949-02-11 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Cornell Univ Photo #6871-15-22 10GeV Linac gun and E. vonBorstal with label (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - #6871-14-31View along Linac with vonBorstal (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - #6871-14-28 same w/o vonBorstal (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Linac Stack early in construction (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - 10 GeV Linac (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Sol Goldberg Corn Univ Photo 6711 roll 11Wilson Lab Construction, Transportation of 10 GeV Magnets (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Cornell Univ Photo (Box 9, Folder 17-18)
  - #6871-15-7,8,9 Linac, E. von Borstal, R. Bower (Box 9, Folder 17-18)
  - #6871-15-4 Linac, E. von Borstal (Box 9, Folder 17-18)
  - #6871-14-14, -27, -28, -29 Linac (Box 9, Folder 17-18)
  - #6871-15-22 Linac, E. von Borstal (Box 9, Folder 17-18)
  - #6871-26-36 Linac, R. Bower (Box 9, Folder 17-18)
  - #6871-26-32, -33 Linac, Bower, H. Edwards (Box 9, Folder 17-18)
  - #6871-25-12 10 GeV Synchrotron (Box 9, Folder 17-18)
  - #6871-25-10 Last Linac Beampipe and 10 GeV Synch. (Box 9, Folder 17-18)
  - #6871-6-21 Synchrotron, von Borstal (Box 9, Folder 17-18)
  - #6871-16-5 Linac (Box 9, Folder 17-18)
  - Cornell Univ Photo Services #1-2538-5 Beam Line “Linac Positron Converter”? (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Early part of 10 Gev Linac (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - 10 GeV Linac Tunnel with linac components unmounted (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Cutaway view of Wilson Lab and Tunnel (later view including LOE) (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Magnet assembly and people (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - 10 GeV tunnel, some with B. MacDaniel (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - 10 Gev Synchrotron table 159 closeup (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Construction of 2nd Wilson Lab cooling tower (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Carl A. Kroch Library #6711, Roll 11 (Printing order included 35) Moving 10 GeV Synchrotron magnets from assembly building to Wilson Lab during construction, 1994-04-29 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Office of Public Information #6871-24-11 Internal lengthwise view of 10 GeV synchrotron magnet showing reflections (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - 10 GeV Magnet Details (Box 9, Folder 22-23)
  - 10 Gev Magnet and Quad details and tunnel, people, transportation, equipment (Box 9, Folder 22-23)
  - 10 GeV magnet details, vacuum chambers, tunnel, people (Box 9, Folder 22-23)
  - Cornell Univ Photo # 6871-20-2 William Woodward surveying in Tunnel (Box 9, Folder 24-26)
  - #6711-10-25 Bicycles in tunnel (Box 9, Folder 24-26)
  - #6711-51-3 Magnet Assembly (Box 9, Folder 24-26)
  - Magnet end section (Box 9, Folder 24-26)
  - Special Magnets (Box 9, Folder 24-26)
  - #6711-11-2, -8, -12, -20, -22 Magnet Transporter (Box 9, Folder 24-26)
  - #6711-8-6, 6711-1-10, -11 Magnet Assembly (Box 9, Folder 24-26)
  - #10678-9 End of Magnet in Tunnel (Box 9, Folder 24-26)
  - #10554-1, -2, -3 Magnet Jacks (Box 9, Folder 24-26)
  - #10767-6 Magnets in Tunnel (Box 9, Folder 24-26)
  - #6871-21-13 Magnet Assembly with J. Fuller and Don Edwards (Box 9, Folder 24-26)
  - #6871-21-9 Magnet Laminations with Fuller and Edwards (Box 9, Folder 24-26)
  - #6871-24-21 “View into vacuum system of Cornell synchrotron ...” (Box 9, Folder 24-26)
  - 10 GeV synchrotron tunnel, 3 with B. McDaniel (Box 9, Folder 24-26)
  - #6711-7-4 Wilson Lab 10GeV Tunnel C. Ball, R.Smith, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 24-26)
  - #6711-10-3 same with R. Smith, C. Chaffey, C. Ball (Box 9, Folder 24-26)
  - #6711-10-6 R. Matyas 10GeV Synchrotron (Box 9, Folder 24-26)
  - #6711-4-5 Magnet fabrication with R. Prouty, J. Fuller, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 24-26)
  - #6711-7-4 Magnet fabrication R. Prouty, J. Fuller (Box 9, Folder 24-26)